[Music]
welcome back let's get straight to the
management of icici lombard the
company's posted a steady quarter even
as claims rise with return of normalcy
to discuss the quarter going by we're
now joined by bhargav dasgupta who's the
md and ceo at icici lombard general
insurance thanks a lot mr dos gupta for
joining in looking at your numbers and
out there you know the combined ratio
that's come down to around
103.2 this compares with 104.5 but it's
still at elevated levels here on here it
was close around
101.8 how do you see this trending and
can it at any time go below that 100
mark because you know once it goes below
100 we understand that it's profitable
above 100 still loss-making
thanks for having me
and just to answer your question you're
right that you know over last quarter
there's been an improvement now i just
said the context uh if you look at the
last year similar period number that
you're comparing
uh today we are integrated with the
bharti access business when we had
announced the transaction uh at that
point in time bharti access combined was
120 and we had said that when we
integrate it will come to around 104 and
it will take us a few quarters to bring
it in line with our
you know normal numbers of uh close to
100 percent
so you have to see it in that context so
how if you look at
moving ahead uh clearly we will see
combined ratio improve
uh we will have to decide you know how
fast we want to do that because we are
also investing heavily in terms of some
of our distribution
channels so if you look at what we've
talked about uh you know this year
we've added uh we've kind of offered
about a thousand people for to run our
health agency team uh office 750 have
already joined yes now when people come
on board it's a it's a incremental cost
you don't see the revenue immediately so
that's an investment that we are making
similarly for digital
this year we became the first large
insurance company to move our entire you
know uh applications and and and uh you
know you know and technology to the
cloud so we have a kind of a double you
know what i mean in the sense that you
know migration we are maintaining our
on-prem system yeah we the integration
going so all of that will take a bit of
time so but directionally in the long
term clearly focuses on sustainable
business all right
let's get back to the point then how
soon can you get to 100 sometime in this
year or
do you have some guidance that you could
give us a particular quarter that you
have targeted
no i don't want to specify any specific
any particular quarter it's difficult to
predict that but the point that i'm
making is that it will take us couple of
quarters to streamline and get the
benefits of the synergy for the two
entities okay and that we believe should
happen during this year uh we are
expecting significant synergies but in
terms of the investment that we are
making uh that will sustain for some
more uh time so it will take a bit more
time than uh than you know a few
quarters to come back within 100 okay
all right the other question i had is
that your loss ratios across the motor
third party your uh you know od as well
as your health they're all higher on a
sequential basis
how do you see these trending the
country normalizing post covet
so if you look at let's pick up health
right so as an industry uh you know
collectively we've paid about 25 000
crores of health claims now if you look
at the industry's profitability we make
roughly about four to five thousand
crores as an industry and this is one
industry which has taken this larger
shock hasn't gone back and asked for any
help from anyone uh for us in isis in
lombard we had roughly about 550 crores
plus uh hit because of covert for the
year just for this quarter the wave 3
impact has been there not obviously as
big as the wave 2 but still about 27
crores of covet hit
our sense is that if i look at the
retail book that we are writing today
the health loss ratios should you know
come down going ahead because this
forward impact we believe is one of we
are hoping is one of
and that will go away on the motor side
uh you know on the third party again
there is a pretty high inflation because
it's driven by court orders we've not
seen a price increase from the regulator
because this is regulated the price here
for the last three years we are hopeful
for a small increase that they're
talking about which we'll see uh this
year so again we are hoping that the
motor loss ratios will stabilize we
don't see it coming down significantly
from this level unless pricing intensity
or competition that we are seeing comes
down on on the pricing itself you know
uh can you quantify the kind of increase
that you are anticipating in third party
and
is there enough uh on the table for you
to go ahead and take a price hike on own
damage as well and importantly what does
that happen uh what does that do to your
loss ratio there i mean if the small
price like that you're talking about if
you could quantify that that comes by uh
how would that change your loss ratio
there
yeah so
that's a great point so if you look at
the inflation that we see in third party
prices uh there is no uh public data of
what the inflation is but our belief is
that the inflation is a double digit
number that's how we predict and that's
how we reserve different companies have
different norms we but we believe that
the inflation is double digit and that's
how we reserve uh but the increase that
we are talking about on a portfolio
basis that is being proposed by the
ministries about three percent so in a
sense it's not uh really adequate we
have to do a lot more work in terms of
uh managing the claims uh you know
particularly the fraudulent claims you
know these are court ordered claims so
you can't do anything about the size of
the ticket size of the claims but what
you can do is preventing the frontline
claims that we see in the sector so we
are hoping that that is something that
we will see benefit of secondly we are
seeing some improvement in terms of the
frequency of accidents in this country
and that's been a secular positive trade
trend so in terms of number of claims
also we expect some reduction so we
think the tp loss ratios kind of
from what we've seen for the q4 should
hold uh you know going ahead
on the old damage side we are we've
actually taken some small price
increases uh but that's largely to
defray the inflationary effect that we
are seeing on the uh on the repair side
okay all right mr
plan you know i'm just having a look at
it and on a year and your basis your
motor uh own damage share in business
that's dropped
how do you see this trending go ahead
you know just to give a number i think
as a percentage of business it's falling
closer around 300 bits
yes that's largely driven by the fact
that
if you see for the sector motor was
traditionally the largest segment this
year for the industry as a whole motor
has become the second biggest sector
health has become number one again two
drivers one because of the pandemic
health demand or health insurance demand
has significantly picked up uh so
you know that's one uh tailwind in favor
of the health sector on the motor side
on the other hand we've had headwinds
because
new vehicle sales have been muted two
wheeler has had two consecutive years of
degrowth motor fuc and that's largely we
believe demand driven motor use if you
look at it's been a supply driven
constraint so new vehicle sales have
come down
our viewers the next in the coming year
uh both should correct uh we are hopeful
that the supply constraint you know will
will get ironed out in the next few
months and we are sensing that the
two-wheeler demand is beginning to show
some positive signs uh so we hope that
that part will come back so i think
motor as a share will uh you know go
back up a little but health we believe
will continue to remain the biggest
segment for the general insurance
industry if we take that point enough
about the business uh mr das gupta you
know now a couple of questions that the
stock market would like to know about uh
uh the the float itself or the flow in
in the stock icici bank earlier had
indicated that you know they're looking
to lower their stake from 48 percent to
around 30 percent do you have any
indicative timeline of when that happens
have you any heard anything from them
that's one and on axa itself bharti
holds the i mean 3.7 have they indicated
uh you know an intention to stay
invested or exit at some point this is
post tax ideal of course
yeah of course uh you know so coming
back to the bank point if you look at
the banking regulation act in india a
bank cannot hold
between 30 and 50 in any entity they can
hold more than 50 percent or they have
to hold less than 30 percent so when we
merged bharti axa and isis illuminate
the bank's shareholding came down to 40
in as a consequence to the merger right
so they got a dispensation of uh about
three years uh to continue uh within
this range after which time they you
know by which time they have to bring it
uh below 30. so that's about about 18
months away
and our senses the bank will do what is
good for in our business in terms of the
approach to dilution this is something
that is kind of mandatory uh legally
required and that's why they're doing it
coming to uh bharti you know i can't
really comment on that but my
understanding from our conversations is
that they've indicated that they want to
be long-term investors like follow-up on
that you know icici banks stake can come
down in two ways one they can either
sell it or maybe dilute equity via some
sort of fundraise what are your thoughts
will they be selling it or will there be
any sort of fundraise because you are
investing in the business as well like
you said
you know from our perspective we don't
need to raise capital we've not raised
capital for a long period of time
because the intrinsic business is you
know throwing cash so if you look at our
solvency we are at about 2.45 times why
the regulatory requirement is
1.5 and we believe the solvency will
increase because the covert claim impact
on the solvency that we had this year
will hopefully not repeat in the coming
year so we don't need to raise capital
for ourselves but in terms of dilution
there are multiple ways of looking at it
one is uh you know maybe you know sell
these stairs
the stake or uh you know if there are
opportunities for inorganic
you know acquisitions that also could be
another i think we are looking at all
possible uh you know options yeah
everything is on the table okay and we
will collectively do between the bank
shareholders
what is right for our business you
hinted at something inorganic growth
something's on the cards
we've always said we are open oh there's
nothing on the card which is immediately
uh something that we can talk about okay
something comes up we'll very happily
share it with you and we'll be happy to
have you on the show thanks so much mr
dos gupta for joining and giving us a
detailed uh check in terms of your your
review on the business going ahead look
forward to catching up with you rather
soon for the time being though we'll
slip into a short break but it's earning
season so when we return we'll get in
the management of raj rathan global
buyers stay with us
[Music]
you